Ran Duan

English/ Mandarin/ French

Brampton, Ontario

ran.duan@mail.mcgill.ca

416-820-8839

Profile

Three years working experience as Mechanical Designer and Simulation Engineer in automotive industry, Three years experience in Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD), structural analysis with Finite Element Analysis (FEA). Skillful application experience of CAD software SolidWorks and ERP software JobBOSS. Solid knowledge in renewable energy, heat transfer, fluid mechanics, materials and mechanical engineering.

Skills

FEA Software

ANSYS (Fluent, Mechanical, Discovery AIM, Live), SolidWorks Simulation.

CAD Tools Programing

MATLAB, C++.

Other

PLM, BoM, GD&T, JobBOSS, LabView, ImageJ, Microsoft Office, Class 5

SolidWorks (Certified SolidWorks Professional), Creo, Siemens NX, AutoCAD.

Driver's Licences, Adobe (Acrobat, Photoshop, Premiere Pro).

Education

Master of Engineering, Materials Engineering

2017

McGill University, Montreal, Canada.

• Thesis: Simulation of Waste Heat Recovery for Electricity Generation.

Bachelor of Engineering, Mechanical Engineering

2011

North University of China, Shanxi, China.

• University Scholarship for Academic Achievement.

Professional Experience

Engineering Specialist

2019

Aircraft Appliances and Equipment Ltd. Brampton, Ontario, Canada.

Mechanical Simulation Engineer

2018-2019

Kunming Yunnei Power Co., Ltd. Kunming, China.

- Analysis, modeling, computer simulation and optimization of the radiator for multicylinder small bore diesel engine with Finite Element Analysis (FEA).
- According to the simulation requirements, modify the geometry and mesh of the 3D model
- Determine the governing equation of the CFD method, select the discrete method, input the relevant parameters, and solve the problem.
- Visualization of temperature, velocity, pressure, and other parameters.
- Submit ANSYS Fluent and Mechanical simulation results to the mechanical designers and propose optimization recommendations.

Heat Transfer, Fluid Mechanics and Sustainable Materials Processing 2016-2017 Teaching Assistant

McGill University, Montreal, Canada.

 Co-instructed and assisted Prof. Frank Mucciardi with 3 university level engineering courses. Responsibilities including tutorial delivery, grading assignments and exams, demonstrating laboratory sessions, replying Emails from students and leading discussions. Gave lectures of ANSYS tutorial including Fluent, Mechanical and Transient Thermal.

Thermoelectricity Lab Research Assistant

2014-2017

McGill University, Montreal, Canada.

- Conducted research on waste heat recovery for electricity generation with ANSYS Fluent.
- Constructed, modified and optimized the laboratory test setups for testing of the thermoelectricity generator.
- Supervised teams of seven students performing experiments and tracking data.

Thermodynamics of Materials Lab Research Assistant

2012-2013

Concordia University, Montreal, Canada.

• Conducted research on diffusion bonding technology for Ti-5553 alloy.

Mechanical Design Engineer

2011-2012

Kunming Yunnei Power Co., Ltd, Kunming, China.

2013-2014

- Developed and designed two crankshaft flywheels prototypes for crank mechanism to fulfill mechanical requirements.
- Performed 3D designs of parts and assembly with SolidWorks, considering design for manufacturing, assembly and reliability.
- Created 2D drawings with AutoCAD based on tolerance stack-up calculation and manufacturing process.

Professional Certificates

1 Totocolorial Coltinuates	
ANSYS Mechanical and Fluent Professional Training Program	2019
ANSYS Pera Corporation Ltd, Shanghai, China.	
Certified SOLIDWORKS Professional	2019
Dassault Systèmes, Vélizy-Villacoublay, France.	
Workplace Hazardous Materials Information System (WHMIS) Training	2015
McGill University, Montreal, Canada.	

Activities and Interests

Quadcopter Drone and Radio-Control Helicopter Flying

• Certified Professional UAV Operator with Professional Radio Operator Certificate.